

SOFTWARE ENGINEER - IOT\DEVOPS

Curitiba, Paraná, Brazil

□ (+55) 41-992227969 | 🖼 valdeci@outlook.my | 🏕 valde.ci | 🖸 coderade | 🖹 coderade | 🛅 valdeci | 🕲 coderade

Summary_

Software Engineer focused on open-source technologies, I am currently working with IOT, DevOps and FullStack development at Rumo company.

Software Engineer with 6 years of experience, I was able to work mainly with large projects using GIS (Geographic Information System) and IOT (Internet of Things) technologies, DevOps (Deploys automation, configuration management, and so on), as well as websystems and websites for large clients in Brazil and the World.

In addition to experience in large proprietary projects, I have good experience in open-source projects, always focused in following the main standards of code, quality, testability and safety.

Arch Linux User, Java Certified, I have an experience focused on Back-end/DevOps development, but I have a good knowledge of AWS stack technologies (DynamoDB, IOT, Lambda, EC2, SNS, SQS, Kinesis, among others), Containerization (Docker/docker-compose) and technologies like Python, Ruby on Rails, JS, Node.js, PHP, Drupal, Java, React/Redux and React-Native, AngularJS e IONIC, Adobe AEM, ExtJS, PostgreSQL, MySQL and others.

Work Experience

Rumo S.A Curitiba, Brazil

SOFTWARE ENGINEER (DEVOPS/IOT)

Oct. 2017 - PRESENT

- Responsible for the development of real-time communication systems between equipments used by the RUMO trains and Internet (IOT) for data processing such as BI, monitoring, alarms, Machine Learning and etc.
- In this opportunity I worked using the maximum of AWS Stack (EC2, DynamoDB, IOT, S3, Lambda, MQTT, SQS, SNS, Kinesis) for data processing and the Big Data stack (HDFS Hadoop, Cloudera, Impala, Hive, Oracle Analytics Cloud) for our Analytics system. In addition to using the most of the open-source technologies such as Python, Node.Js, Javascript (ES6), Java (Spring), AngularJS/5, React/Redux and others.
- The initial focus of this role was to work in a project for the initiation and improvement of the devices/sensors used in the route by the RUMO's trains. Project which now have an average of 5 million rules executing in the AWS IOT daily for sending data to systems such as PRTG (monitoring) and Oracle Analytics Cloud (BigData) and PowerBI.
- In addition to IOT and Big Data projects, I had the opportunity to be responsible for the implementation of the DevOps methodology in Rumo with the automation of deploys of SOA, OSB and Web projects and an automated Jira tracking using Jenkins. I also was able to help on the migration of VCS system from the Subversion to GIT (Bitbucket) and documentation with Confluence of projects.
- Also, I had the opportunity to work whenever possible as a Full Stack Software Engineer, developing some projects when needed, I worked developing some systems using combination of technologies like: (Flask and React/Redux), (Spring/Angular), (Java/AngularJs 1), (Node.js/React) always thinking on the best technology for determined need.
- In the Rumo technology area we used the best of agile methodologies, using Scrum and Kanban and tools like Bitbucket (GIT) for project and code version management (VCS) and Jira and Confluence for documentation and issues.

Mirum Agency Curitiba, Brazil

FULL STACK SOFTWARE ENGINEER (WEB - MOBILE)

Apr. 2016 - Oct. 2017

- Development and maintenance of Mobile and Web applications using JS, IONIC, AngularJS, Cordova, Node.js, Adobe AEM, PHP, Codelgniter, Drupal, MySQL and other technologies.
- In this opportunity I worked developing web apps for big clients on the world. One of our biggest clients was the Activia Danone websites (Drupal 8 websites), The West Ham United team website (Drupal 8) and the Ebook App for the Learning Factory company (Adobe AEM and IONIC)
- In the IT area of Mirum we used agile methodologies, using Scrum and Kanban and tools like Bitbucket, Gitlab, Github (GIT) for project and code version management (VCS) and Jira and Confluence for documentation and issues.

VeltecLondrina, Brazil

SOFTWARE ENGINEER (GIS - WEB)

Jul. 2015 - Mar. 2016

- I this opportunity I worked as a Full Stack developer using technologies such Ruby on Rails, Node.js, PostgreSQL, ExtJS, Python, ShellScript, Georeferencing, Java, AngularJS and others
- My main goal in the company was to be responsible for migrating the company's Georeferencing System (first development in Delphi and .shp files) to a microservice architecture taking full advantage of open source technologies like Ruby on Rails, Postgresql, Postgis, Python, OpenStreetMap, Java, Shellscript, AngularJs, EXTJS, D3.js, OpenLayers, Leaflet and others.
- In the area of technology of Veltec we used agile methodologies using Scrum (daily meeting, Pair Programming, Code Review and etc) and tools like Bitbucket (GIT) for project and code version management (VCS) and Redmine and Confluence for documentation and issues.

Z3 WEB Digital Agency Londrina, Brazil

FULL STACK SOFTWARE ENGINEER

Jan. 2015 - Jul. 2015

- Development and maintenance of websites using technologies such as Html5, PHP, Css, CakePHP, Javascript, Wordpress, Jquery, MySQL, among others.
- In the Z3 Web technology area we used tools like Bitbucket (Git) for project and code version management (VCS) and RunRunIt for task management.

Amcor Cambé, Brazil

IT Support - Intern Jan, 2013 - Dec. 2014

· Technical support for Windows and Linux systems, Lotus Notes and ERP System - Progress, backup systems and etc.

• Support for the Head Office in Brazil and offices in São Paulo.

Certifications

Oracle Certified Associate, Java SE 7 Programmer

Curitiba, Brazil

ORACLE

May. 2014

• A Java SE 7 Oracle Certified Associate (OCA) has built a foundational understanding of Java, while acquiring knowledge of general programming.

Expert User Londrina, Brazil

RUNRUN.IT May. 2013

• A RunRun.it Expert User has an awesome knowledge about the RunRun.it system.

Honors & Awards _

INTERNATIONAL

2017 **Finalist (7th / 100)**, The Big Hackathon Campus Party 2017

Oracle Excellence Award, Supervisorio System

São Paulo, Brazil

Curitiba, Brazil

Languages

English Advanced
Portuguese Native
Spanish Elementary

Projects

Open Source Projects

Github

HTTPS://GITHUB.COM/CODERADE

Jan. 2014 - PRESENT

Aug. 2019 - Set. 2019

· Source of my open-source projects.

Rumo Zoom Portal

Rumo

HTTPS://PORTALZOOM.RUMOLOG.COM

· Web application designed to be used as an integration tool between Zoom and Rumo system for meeting scheduling.

- In this project I was be able to develop as a Full Stack Engineer, creating its architecture, developing since the Frontend to the backend, Working as SysOps and Managing its database.
- · As I was the main responsible for this project, I tried to use the best technologies for the project needs and deadline.
- In this way, the project has a backend developed using Python (Flask) and frontend in ReactJS/Redux and Bootstrap, uses a NOSQL database with MongoDB, is served with Nginx and secured with a Let's Encrypt SSL certificate. And everything is up using only a command using Docker/Docker Compose!

WeBrado Portal Brado/Rumo

HTTPS://WE.BRADO.COM.BR

Dec. 2018 - Feb. 2019

Aug. 2018 - PRESENT

- FullStack development in the WeBrado project of the company Brado Logistica also of the group Cosan in Brazil.
- In this project I had the opportunity to work with technologies such as Java 8 and Spring Boot, Nexus Repository, Docker, Kubernetes, Nginx, Redis, Netflix Zuul, Service Discovery (Netflix Eureka), Angular 6, Typescript and etc.

Rumo DevOps SOA/OSB/WEB | SVN to Git migration

Rumo

PROPRIETARY SOFTWARE

- In this project I had the opportunity to participate in the implementation of the DevOps methodology in Rumo with the automation of deploys of SOA, OSB, Web projects, automation of the update of the cards in Jira.
- In addition I had the opportunity to work in the changes of configuration management in the RUMO IT area as the implementation and deployment of migration from SVN Version Control to GIT (Bitbucket) and documentation of projects with Confluence.

Supervisory system Rumo

PROPRIETARY SOFTWARE Sep. 2017 - PRESENT

• Software Project with the goal of implementing and improving real-time communication systems between devices used by the locomotives/trains concessioned by Rumo and Internet of things (IOT) for handling data such as BI, monitoring, Machine Learning and etc.

- The initial focus of the project was the initiation or improvement of the equipment used in the route by the company's RUMO trains running an average of 5 million rules executed daily on the AWS for sending data to systems such as PRTG System (monitoring) and Oracle Analytics Cloud (BigData).
- This project was developed using the maximum of AWS Stack (EC2, DynamoDB, IOT, S3, Lambda, MQTT, SQS, SNS, Kinesis) for data processing and the Big Data stack (HDFS Hadoop, Cloudera, Impala, Hive, Oracle Analytics Cloud) for our Analytics system. In addition to using the most the open-source technologies such as Python, Node.Js, Javascript (ES6), Java, AngularJS and others.

Activia Websites Mirum Agency

HTTPS://WWW.ACTIVIA.US.COM

Nov. 2016 - Jan. 2017

- Development and maintenance of Activia Danone's global websites.
- The sites were developed using the technologies Drupal 8, MySQL, JS, Node.js and others.

Tim Live Website / System Mirum Agency

HTTP://WWW.LIVETIM.COM.BR

Apr. 2016 - Sep. 2016

- Responsible for the website and the back-end development of the Live TIM website the TIM Broadband Internet of Fiber Optics in Brazil.
- Website/ System developed using the technologies PHP, Codelgniter, MySQL, Jquery, Mustache, Sass and etc.

West Ham United F.C. Website

Mirum Agency

HTTP://WWW.WHUFC.COM

Apr. 2016 - Sep. 2016

- Backend Development of the website of the English Soccer Club West Ham United.
- Technologies used: Drupal 8, PHP, JS, MySQL, Sass, Node.js, Bootstrap and others.

Veltec MapSrv System

Veltec

HTTP://VELTEC3G.COM.BR

Jul. 2015 - Feb. 2016

- Web system based on OpenStreetMap stack for creating and processing maps for systems used by customers of the company Veltec. This
 system consists of several modules taking advantage of proprietary and open source projects to enabling editing and rendering maps as well
 other features such as geocoding a proprietary way by the company.
- In the system development was taken advantage of the best open source technologies, using, PostgreSQL, PostGIS, Ruby On Rails, Node.js, Python, used PHP, among others technologies.

Education

PUCPR (Pontifical university Catholic of Parana)

Londrina, Brazil

POSTGRADUATE COURSE - MOBILE APPS DEVELOPMENT (SCIENCE COMPUTER)

Jan. 2016 - Mar. 2018 (Not finished)

 The Majoring Diploma in App Development offers an advanced curriculum in the development of solutions for mobile devices, interrelating methodologies and market technologies.

UNOPAR (Universidade Norte do Paraná)

Londrina Brazil

ASSOCIATE DEGREE IN COMPUTER SCIENCE (SYSTEM ANALYSIS AND DEVELOPMENT) - A3

Jan. 2013 - Dec. 2015

- I got a scholarship to study this course.
- Basic training area of this course aims to integrate the student in the computer field, from the perspective of its object and give the theoretical and practical reasoning for that he can interpret and follow the disciplines of professional area, pointing for relations of Information Technology with the other disciplines.

Instituto Senai Londrina, Brazil

CERTIFICATE PROGRAMM, PROGRAMMING

Jan. 2013 - Dec. 2013

- This course I had the opportunity to study with a scholarship.
- Course will form a professional who will apply the database concepts and use the key technologies related to Java platform for developing systems

Extracurricular Activity

Volunteer Computer Teacher

Londrina, Brazil

VOLUNTEER EXPERIENCE

Feb. 2015 - Sep. 2015

• The CVL, through volunteers, created the Employability Project, whose goal is to empower and guide professionally, people without socioe-conomic conditions for (re) integration to the labor market, working on personal and professional development of these people (Knowledge, Skills, attitudes and Values), and encourage reflection, critical thinking, argumentation, criticality, observation, decision-making, exchange of experiences, teamwork, new technical knowledge, technology and innovation, as well the motivation to start and / or return to regular studies. In this project I act teaching computer classes as a volunteer teacher in PLDA (Patronato Penitentiary of Londrina), aimed at inclusion and citizenship, giving opportunity to the labor market and social life for egresses of the criminal justice system and also people who can't pay for a course.

For more details, please take a look on my LinkedIn profile.

SEPTEMBER 8, 2019 VALDECI GOMES · RÉSUMÉ